<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<!-- Generated using X-Studio -->
<language id="44">
	<page id="9973" title="SWM3 customization" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="1">1</t> <!-- Activate Era system (0 to disable and make NPCs start with strong squadrons which not evolve over time. Change requires new game.) -->
		<t id="2">1</t> <!-- Rebels use their outposts like jump beacons (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="3">1</t> <!-- Faction and plot stage dependent NPC production boosters. Examples: Republic midgame has powerful Clone Wars militarization. Rebel Alliance always builds more cost efficient due to secret support. New Republic very lategame boom, etc. (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="4">1</t> <!-- Rebel Cell ability - random NPC sectors frequently join (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="5">16</t> <!-- amount of rebel sectors up to which Rebel Cell ability is active (default 16) -->
		<t id="6">64800</t> <!-- Minimum time between two Rebel Cell ability activations, in seconds (default 18h: 64800) -->
		<t id="7">93600</t> <!-- Maximum time between two Rebel Cell ability activations, in seconds (default 26h: 93600) -->
		<t id="8">1</t> <!-- Empire is allowed to annihilate the Rebels. They won't actually be successful if you play with Rebel Cells activated (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="9">8</t> <!-- AI will not invade rebel faction that owns less than or equal to this number of sectors. (default: 8) -->
		<t id="10">18</t> <!-- before Mandalorian Uprising event happens AI will not invade republic faction that owns less than or equal to this number of sectors. (default: 18) -->
		<t id="11">1</t> <!-- Rebels do deep strike invasions like Mandalorians (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="12">0</t> <!-- show rather useless onscreen messages about claims or protectorates expiring (hidden by default, 1 to show) -->
		<t id="13">50</t> <!-- remaining percentage of Rebel sectors after gamestart, rest given to Republic (default 50) -->
		<t id="14">85</t> <!-- remaining percentage of New Republic sectors after gamestart, rest given to Empire (default 85) -->
		<t id="15">4</t> <!-- amount of Miner Workers allowed on player outposts. WARNING any change to ongoing savegames requires that you restart ALL outpost Workers  (default 4) -->
		<t id="16">1</t> <!-- jump beacon construction must be unlocked with a mission to first conquer any Hyperlane sector of your choice (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="17">0</t> <!-- player jump beacons outside Hyperlane sectors dont work and get ignored (off by default, 1 to enable) -->
		<t id="18">20</t> <!-- global research discount after completing projects in research stations in percent of project cost (default 20, disable with 0) -->
		<t id="19">1</t> <!-- Katana fleet event. New Republic lategame comeback with many Dreadnought heavy cruisers (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="20">1</t> <!-- lategame Rebel Alliance extinction. Quickly merges with New Republic (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="21">1</t> <!-- lategame Republic extinction. Quickly merges with Galactic Empire (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
		<t id="22">1</t> <!-- lategame megawar. New Republic total war against Galactic Empire (on by default, 0 to disable) -->
	</page>

	<page id="17" title="Boardcomp. objects" desc="" voice="yes">
		<t id="2103">Imperial Police License</t>
		<t id="2303">Alliance Police License</t>
		<t id="3771">Pirate Ship</t>
		<t id="3781">Pirate Base</t>
		<t id="15351">Imperial Outpost</t>
		<t id="15353">New Republic Outpost</t>
		<t id="15355">Separatist Outpost</t>
		<t id="15357">Alliance Outpost</t>
		<t id="15359">Republic Outpost</t>
		<t id="15361">Mandalorian Outpost</t>
		<t id="96953">Katana Dreadnought</t>
		<t id="96954">The Katana fleet, also known as the Dark Force, was a task force of 200 Dreadnaught-class heavy cruisers launched by the Galactic Republic during its final decades of existence, as part of an attempt to restore the Republic Navy to its long-gone glory. The fleet, however, was lost on its maiden voyage when a hive virus drove its crews insane and the task force's captain jumped the ships blindly into hyperspace.\n\nKatana Dreadnoughts are special in that they have no shielding but a very tough hull strength. This makes them very good at tanking against fighters and small laser fire. They're also highly automated which makes them cheap and easy to maintain. But they are slightly undergunned and require frequent repairs, which is a big downside.</t>
	</page>

	<page id="1000" title="Job names" desc="" voice="yes">
		<t id="103">Alliance</t>
		<t id="119">Mandalorian</t>
	</page>

	<page id="1263" title="Shipclass IDs" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="19101">I</t>
		<t id="19102">N</t>
		<t id="19103">A</t>
		<t id="19104">C</t>
		<t id="19105">R</t>
		<t id="19106">S</t>
		<t id="19108">H</t>
		<t id="19110">M</t>
	</page>

	<page id="1266" title="Racenames" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="3">Rebel Alliance</t>
		<t id="6">Sith</t>
		<t id="7">Sith Scouts</t>
		<t id="8">Pirates</t>
		<t id="16">Sith OCV</t>
	</page>

	<page id="4000" title="SWM3 Mandalorian Plot" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="1">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]quite an empire you built from nothing. We are the same you know. Two natural leaders, now stranded in an ocean of opportunity. Look around you! This galaxy is weak and ripe for conquest. I see potential for us. That`s why i`m offering you to become my right hand and join our Crusade!\n\nIf thats going too fast for you, then so be it. You`ve already earned some respect and my warfleets would spare you. For now...\n\nBut if you accept my generous offer i will put my pirate dogs back on the leash so that we can properly trade with each other. That would spare me quite some expenses. If  these economic allocations would flow to your empire instead we could transform it into a capable force in no time. I would share my entire ship technology with you. Together we can guide our people to victory.\n\nOf course all of that can only happen after your public vow to our cause.\n\nTo round it up nicely for you i`ll even add one of my personal Keldabe battlecruisers on top. Fully decked out and ready to roll. And i'm covering its entire upkeep for you.\n\nYou get half a day to think this over.\n\n\n[yellow][u]Consequences:[/u][/yellow]\n\n[white]A\) Stay Neutral:[/white]\nno consequences\n\n[white]B\) Reject him and Fight:[/white]\n[red]- permanent war against Mandalorians[/red]\n[red]-- if they manage to grow very large they'll stop attacking others and only focus on annihilating you until you reach the lategame[/red]\n[green]+ clears any negative reputation with all main factions once[/green]\n[green]+ get 10.000 reputation and 4 favor points with all main factions[/green]\n[green]++ no more reputation penalty from conquering adjacent sectors until you reach the lategame[/green]\n\n[white]C\) Join the Crusade:[/white]\n[red]----- permanent wars against all main factions[/red]\n[red]--- Lategame will begin 2 days later whether you're ready or not[/red]\n[green]++ get 1 Keldabe M2 with free maintenance[/green]\n[green]+ get mandalorian reputation rank 10[/green]\n[green]+++ indirect control of Mandalorian faction \(unlimited favors\)[/green]\n[green]+++ no more pirates from mandalorian outposts for the rest of the game[/green]\n[green]+++ maintenance discount for the rest of the game \(30\%\)[/green]\n[green]+++ unlocks all mandalorian ship blueprints \(including capships!\)[/green]\n[green]++++ instant specialization levelup on your current outposts[/green]\nthis takes your maximum allowed specialization \(default 50\%\) as base and adds another 20\% bonus ontop. The bonus can't be aquired in any other way! But it degrades if you have more than 4 outposts before your commitment.\n\n</t>
		<t id="2">[white]A: Neutral \(easy\)[/white] \(no timer\)</t>
		<t id="3">[white]B: Fight \(difficult\)[/white] \(%s minutes left\)</t>
		<t id="4">[white]C: Join \(difficult\)[/white] \(%s minutes left\)</t>
		<t id="5">[white]D: Delay[/white]</t>
		<t id="6">Hey boss! Subspace radio chatter just stepped up tenfold! The Mandalorians have started their insurrection across multiple sectors! It`s wierd. They praise some hero all the time. Apparently this guy orchestrated all these strange terrorist attacks on the local economy from before. Not only did he have the pirate gangs in his pocket all along! No, he also built warfleets in secret!\n\nOur analysts predict that the other main factions will spread fear among their citizens in order to drive war support through the roof. [yellow]Expect more militarization across all factions.[/yellow] But they will need long to build up first. That may give these new arrivals some time to rampage almost unchallenged!\n\nWe should remain cautious until we`ve put all this into perspective. We must learn who this leader is and what he is up to.</t>
		<t id="7">And here we go. Our mysterious hero has sent a special offer.\n\n\n[yellow]To see this special offer go to your journal \(player console\) and click on the mission entry.[/yellow]</t>
		<t id="8">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]So you have chosen to ignore me, yes? That's pretty bold of you. Your insolence makes me chuckle a bit.\n\nBut don't fool yourself! Get in my way or hinder the Crusade and i will end you!\n\nLets see how long we get along.</t>
		<t id="9">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]Well, well, well... Seems like we got a real hero right here. Prepare yourself for glorious battle!\n\n\n[yellow]!!! Strategy advice: !!![/yellow]\nIts likely that the Mandalorians will expand further. This will take them long, but IF they can establish a sizable empire they will stop attacking other factions and focus entirely on annihilating YOU completely. Their deep strike fleets will invade your sectors wherever they might be. Your only chance to end this is to steadily expand your empire in order to reach the final plot stage. This will stop the Mandalorians from attacking only you and they will invade other factions again. Their other enemies will also become much stronger which should help you.</t>
		<t id="10">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]Yes. Let us fuel the flames of war together! My pirate raiders are putting their weapons down and have been sent over to help make your outposts more efficient. The Keldabe i promised to you is waiting in one of our sectors.\nTell us if you need protection or if we should leave certain sectors for you to claim.\nI expect that you immediately start to bring glory to our Crusade!\n\n\n[yellow]!!! Strategy advice: !!![/yellow]\nYour empire has just been supercharged for a quick military rush. The outposts you have right now can produce cheaper and quicker than any other outpost. So try to build all your ships in these original outposts. These are forever the most valuable part of your empire. Never loose them if possible!\n\nFrom now on you only have a single remaining allied faction. But you are a powerful team because you can influence them in the Ministry of War! Call for help, trader priority, satellite service. Or even give them invasion targets by letting them know what sectors they should attack or keep for you to claim.\n\nAll other factions want you dead and they are slowly growing their forces stronger as you read this. Right now most of them are still super weak, so try to conquer many sectors quickly!\n\nYou only have 2 days until the final plot stage gets activated. This will make your enemies very strong and your Mandalorian friends weak. You should help them to grow larger during the next couple days! Now is the time to get a decent headstart by conquering lots of territory!</t>
		<t id="11">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]Understood, you don't want to get involved. This works for me. Your small empire is no worthy opponent anyway. I've instructed my officers to ravage your territory less. But a few of us will just ignore me and go raiding your sectors as pirates anyway. And i won't stop them. Taking from the weak is in a Mandalorians nature.\n\nAnd just a fair warning. If you ever get in my way or hinder our Crusade. Lets just say that wouldn't be too healthy for you, shall we?</t>
		<t id="12">[author]\033RMandalore the Ultimate[/author]The Mandalorians have grown strong. Nothing will stop our Crusade. You should've killed us when you had the chance.\n\nPrepare to die!\n\n\n[yellow]!!! Strategy advice: !!![/yellow]\nTheir empire has become too large and confident. This is bad news for you. Your feud with their leader is not forgotten. Now he is after you!\nMandalorian battlegroups have deep strike ability. They can reach your sectors even over long distance! The Mandalorians won't launch any more invasions against other factions. You alone have become their only prime target.\n\nThere is only way to stop them. You must reach the lategame. This will weaken them considerably and also beef up their enemies. There are two ways to get to the lategame. Conquer 20 sectors or complete the terraforming quest.\n\n[red]Whatever you've been doing, get the move on right now or face annihilation !!![/red]</t>
		<t id="13">[author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Quick reminder about the Mandalorian offer, boss. We only got [red]1 hour left[/red]. If we don't make a decision we will stay neutral. Maybe you should be so polite and actually answer them.\n\n[yellow]To see the offer again go to your personal journal in the player console and click on the mission entry.[/yellow]</t>
	</page>
	<page id="4001" title="SWM3 Katana Fleet" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="1">[author]\033GVolkhart[/author][blue]The Katana fleet, also known as the Dark Force, was a task force of 200 Dreadnaught-class heavy cruisers launched by the Galactic Republic during its final decades of existence, as part of an attempt to restore the Republic Navy to its long-gone glory. The fleet, however, was lost on its maiden voyage when a hive virus drove its crews insane and the task force's captain jumped the ships blindly into hyperspace.[/blue]\n\nThe New Republic has just discovered a large portion of this lost fleet! %s ships to be exact. These special prototypes are highly automated and so the New Republic could immediately deploy %s additional Battlegroups!\n\nThis inspired many Rebel sectors to join and stop their independent guerilla fighting.\nThe political situation in the Old Republic is crumbling. Multiple systems have lost their belief in democracy and joined the Galactic Empire. Global tensions are on the rise.\n\n[yellow]During their long voyage the Dreadnought cruisers of the Katana fleet lost all their deflector shields. But their hull strength is still very tough and right now the Katana fleet has a serious capship numbers advantage against any foe. Don't try to attack them with swarms of fighters as they only do little hull damage.\nThose %s new Battlegroups will be almost unstoppable for some time. But they can't be repaired and will eventually get weaker.[/yellow]</t>
		<t id="2">[author]\033GVolkhart[/author]The Galactic Empire has just declared that they will not tolerate the New Republic any longer. In return the New Republic has sworn to liberate the galaxy from imperial oppression! The two powers are clashing in a total war. Right now the Empire still got much larger territory, but the New Republic has the Katana fleet. So we can't be sure who is gonna win.\nTheir relations have become so bad that no more truces will be signed.\n\nHow should we react to this conflict? Some systems have already pledged their allegiance and joined either side. Should we pick one too?\n\nWe could also watch and let them weaken each other. But remember that the Sith invasions are also approaching rapidly!\n\n[yellow]From now on\n1\) the Rebel Alliance will not gain any more sectors from its special ability. Instead Rebel sectors will join the New Republic. This goes much quicker and the Alliance will vanish.\n2\) sectors of the Republic will join the Galactic Empire until the ancient behemoth of democracy is completely gone.\n3\) The New Republic and the Galactic Empire will try to completely wipe each other out.\n\nWhatever you want to do now, get ready for a megawar![/yellow]</t>
		<t id="3">[author]\033GTutorial[/author]Research stations can unlock every ship blueprint. Your personal console has an overview of all research stations.\nResearch speed depends on the sector stat and is not affected by population\n\n[yellow]Usually its a good idea to start unlocking a set of basic ship types that you couldn't get with the Data scanner.\nYou'll need the blueprints for a TS, a TS Miner variant, a TL, and for one or more smaller military ships like fighters, TM, or M6. Then maybe start researching your first capital ship like an M7.[/yellow]\n\nYour researchers will get better over time. Every completed project adds a small amount of its cost to a global discount which reduces all future project costs.\nUnlocking more capships after the first one will be much quicker.\n\nEach research station can also be converted into a Hacking station by spending a perk point from the local Outpost. But that completely changes their purpose and disables ship blueprint research. </t>
		<t id="4">[author]\033RDeath Watch[/author]Heyja! We are the [red]Death Watch[/red]. You might've seen us in the news where they like to call us criminals and terrorists. Oh how little do they understand. Soon they will.\n\nAnyway, we noticed that you have just established your first research station. We'd like to borrow it. You see, we are nothing more than a scattered group and don't have much resources. Recently we captured a spy in our headquarters and got hold of his datapad. Torturing the guy we learned that he stole information from the New Republic. Other sources could confirm that they are onto something really big.\nThe New Republic is the youngest faction in this spacetime anomaly. They tend to have the best archives, historians and technology. That's why i think this datapad will lead us to some kind of treasure. And maybe we can steal it right from under their noses.\n\nHelp us and we'll split the reward 50:50. You can trust us. We are warriors of Mandalore and no ordinary scoundrels!\n\n\n[yellow]Decrypt the datapad with your research station.[/yellow]</t>
		<t id="5">[author]\033RDeath Watch[/author]Apparently the New Republic is out searching for the legendary Katana fleet.\n\n[blue]The Katana fleet, also known as the Dark Force, was a task force of 200 Dreadnaught-class heavy cruisers launched by the Galactic Republic during its final decades of existence, as part of an attempt to restore the Republic Navy to its long-gone glory. The fleet, however, was lost on its maiden voyage when a hive virus drove its crews insane and the task force's captain jumped the ships blindly into hyperspace.[/blue]\n\nUnfortunately the coordinates on this datapad are protected by a masterkey. So we can't simply go and claim the prize. But at least its confirmed that our traitor knew about at least a couple of the lost Dreadnoughts. They must be somewhere around here. Go search in Unknown sectors!\nMaybe we find the missing republican code and then decipher where the rest of the fleet is.</t>
		<t id="6">[author]\033RDeath Watch[/author]You got the ship, good! The Death Watch also discovered and claimed the second one. I bet the navigational computer of your Dreadnought looks equally bad as ours. Nobody really knew where they were hanging around all these decades, but damn?! What must these guys possibly have been through? The deflector shields are completely fried too.\n\nIf we share our results we might get closer to the rest of the fleet.\nResearch your fragment and give us the results. Then we'll hand over our intel from the second ship.\n\n[yellow]Katana Dreadnoughts are not particularly powerful, but still special. They don't cost you any maintenance, are quite mobile and pretty tanky, especially against small lasers. But their damage and range are limited and they always immediately receive permanent hull damage. Like every other ship they repair automatically and for free when docked in an Outpost.\n\nYou can never build more of these.[/yellow]</t>
		<t id="7">[author]\033RDeath Watch[/author]Hmm, that seems to lead us to more locations. The exact coordinates are corrupted again, damnit!\n\n[yellow]But apparently its somewhere in Sith territory. Go search their sectors![/yellow]\n\nWe'll go in the opposite direction. But be careful this time!\nThe Sith frequently launch raids which pass through hidden hyperlanes inside their stations. Last year we had an opportunity to steal this teleporting tech, but busted it. The Rebel Alliance could beat us to it.</t>
		<t id="8">[author]\033RDeath Watch[/author]I fear this is the end of the line my friend. Death Watch found a second pair of Katana ships, but without any working navcomputer. That's a shame. This lead is cold!\n\nWell, at least both of our organizations got a few free capships to start poke something with, eh?\n\nMaybe our paths will cross again. See you around!\n\n[yellow]The Mandalorian Death Watch just received 3 Dreadnought heavy cruisers. They only use them for piracy. These ships are neutral to you but might hurt the local economy pretty bad.[/yellow]</t>
	</page>

	<page id="9972" title="Mayhem 3" desc="" voice="no">
		<t id="1801">[justify][author]\033CEngineer[/author]Sir,\n\nmy team has installed \033C{1}\033X special scanner on your ship.\n\n\033WYou have acquired a Data Scanner. This device allows you to scan any ship in order to unlock its blueprint for construction in your future Outposts. Unlike cargo scanning, data scanning is a safe and free process. To start scanning a ship, you must first assign a special hotkey from the Control settings menu, at the bottom of the Interface tab. Scanning takes some time and to unlock a blueprint, you often need multiple scans on different ships of the same type. This can already unlock smaller ships, but for bigger types you`ll need to build Research stations in your sectors. Note that if you lose your Data Scanner, you will be able to make another one from your Outposts. Be careful though, it`s an expensive equipment![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="1802">[author]\033WTutorial[/author]\n[center]\033YFirst steps[/center][justify]\n\n\n\033WMayhem includes a lot of redesigned menus and hotkeys. Go to your Controls settings, Interface tab, then you`ll find all the new hotkeys at the bottom. Start with the personal console. From there you can reach almost everything else.\n\nThe galaxy will not change much until you complete your Ascension goals. This is your path to become a leader again and control territory.\nRegardless of which Ascension path you have chosen, there are certain things which are always recommended to prepare your future empire building. Don`t focus too much on any single aspect.\n\nExplore!\nIt`s important to get to know the galaxy map and sector stats. For the most part you don`t need to know whats exactly in all those sectors.\nYou also DON`T need a satellite network  yet. Right now your ships can`t quickly reach distant sectors anyway. Too many early satellites just waste time and money.\n\nCollect Ships!\nYour empire requires a few haulers and also military ships to defend your sectors. Check your message log for a Remnant Signal hint. With at least 2 haulers and half a dozen fighters you should be prepared for what`s to come after the Ascension.\nBut keep an eye on your maintenance cost. At this stage it is often not worth it to keep very expensive ships like M6, because they can`t catch quick pirates and generally don`t do anything useful for you yet. Don`t fear loosing ships. In Mayhem 3 you generally can`t loose hours of progress that easily.\n\nEarn Money!\nInitially you will need to buy important resources and constantly pay upkeep. There are plenty of ways and additional early game activities to make money.\nRegister your ship for cargo smuggling or passenger taxi transport. Missions can only be accepted when actually docking and they are tracked by Mayhems own custom journal in your player console.\nEarly trading yields much more relative value than it does in other mods, even if the competition from other traders can be tough in areas around neutral corporation stations with their additional traders. Don`t shy away from buying something at a higher than average price! Even small margins can be much more valuable than it might seem at first.\nLoot and bailed ships can often be found in invasion sectors. Check your sector list in the ministry of war to find these. You can also search for HOT alert levels on the galaxy map. These are the locations where some fighting is going on. Weapon loot can only be sold at Markus corporation trading stations which are often located in Imperial space.\n\nRaise Reputation!\nIt`s absolutely NOT important to reach high ranks with major factions. That doesn`t unlock any new ships or items to buy. You mostly just need to make sure that your reputation doesn`t get negtative until you`ve established yourself.\nYou will need a certain reputation reserve to use as a diplomatic currency. Upon conquering sectors which are adjacent to other factions you have to spend some reputation points to prevent that they get mad and attack you.\nActivities which earn money are usually also good souces of reputation. Missions and taxi transport are some of the best early game options. But killing enemies for the faction you want to be best buddies with is even better.\n\n\nIf you need to read this message again, you`ll find it in your message log.\n\nGood luck![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="1803">[justify][author]\033WTutorial[/author]\033WAs a private pilot, you are not allowed to dock to the Outposts of other factions. These stations have additional trading restrictions. Which means that they don`t just sell everything they have on stock to you. They will try to keep certain amounts of important strategic resources for themselves and they also won`t buy stupidly large amounts of all the crap you might be trying to sell to them.\n\nSo what you can never do in Mayhem is simply docking a ship to a faction outpost and trade goods like usual with the slider. It doesn`t matter if that is your playership or some other ship you control remotely. There are only two ways how you can trade with outposts.\n\n1\) using Trade Run: Buy or Sell commands\n2\) automated Trader Worker ships which must be homebased to your own stations.\n\nBoth of these commands have to respect the additional trade restrictions. So for example when the Trade Run can`t to buy some resource from, this doesn`t mean that nobody has this resource on stock. It just means that nobody wants to sell it to you because he doesn`t even have enough for his own demand.\nThe Station Information screen in your player console can show you this additional layer of trade thresholds for each station.\n\nThe fact that there is a real economy remains important throughout the entire game. Many of the former magic resource sinks are not available! That means that you should try to build a balanced economy according to actual demand and not just focus too much on mass producing a few products which make the most money! You might not be able to sell them in sufficient numbers![/justify]</t>
		<t id="1805">[justify][author]\033WTutorial[/author]\033WYou have just built your first Outpost, congratulations!\n\nYour first Outpost contains some precious resources to get you started; use them to build your first stations and ships. At this point, you should get more station crafting resources. But very soon you also need to worry about basic defense. A small fighter wing is usually enough to deal with stray pirate scum.\n\nDepending how dangerous your starting location is, you might want to keep an eye on your TS ships at first. If you send them out to buy valuable resources from other factions and they have to cross unknown sectors, then it`s often advisable to form convoy groups and have all your few military ships follow as protection. Buy what you need and then return with the entire group.\n\nYou are now able to setup automated ships, called Workers. As a rule of thumb you should own about 100.000 credits of spare cash for each Trader worker. If you don`t have that much, it may be wise to delay your first Traders, as these ships require some investment before they can bring you the first profits. Consider starting with a Tug or Looter Worker. The former can be an M5 for speed \(Tugs don`t need to be carriers\), the latter a TS for cargo or a M6 for survivability.\n\nYour Workers can be killed by Pirates or Sith patrols. When dangerous sectors are identified, you can either blacklist them, or build a small group of fighters to escort your most precious Workers. You can even turn the worker into a fleet commander and setup advanced fleet features for his escort.\n\nWhen you`re ready to build your first Traders, you should adjust their allowed budget by going into the Logistics-&gt;Traders section, and change the `External trade: import maximum value` setting to a lower value. You don`t want them to spend all your money on a single trade!\n\nDon`t be too quick when choosing your first perks. Leaving 1 slot open for some time is actually a wise decision. The No Food Consumption perk is often a great early choice, because it saves you a lot of money and makes your future sector choices much more flexible.\n\nWhile everything is being setup, you should continue to earn money and reputation, or scan some important ships, such as miners. After a few hours, you should start thinking about your global strategy; where to build your next Outposts, what ships to research, what investments you want to make, etc.\n\nGood luck![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="1806">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Glad to have you back, boss!\n\nLet me fill you in about the political situation in these parts.\n\nEntire star systems of different factions arrived here roughly a year ago. They all brought their different backgrounds and feuds with them. I see an age of war coming.\n\nThose who came from a more advanced timeline could piece our shared history together. They told everyone about the Infinite Empire of the Rakata, about the Jedi on Tython. Stories from the Old Republic against the ancient Sith. The Mandalorian wars, all the way to the proclamation of the first Galactic Empire and its fall.\n\nOur team wasn`t slacking, boss. We already made some contacts. This entire situation is a great opportunity to build our own empire among the others!\n\nAccording to our analysts, the other factions are still quite cautious. The intensity of all fighting is still low. We can expect that they will change their fleet doctrines and build new ship types over time. Like it happened historically in the old world, just much faster. Too much advanced knowledge got stranded here. The technology is already circulating and you can`t keep that a secret forever. Make sure to use your new Data Scanner to gather some of that tech for our science division. We`re gonna need it later.\n\nA particularly aggresive group of mandalorian Death Watch has recently started to conduct terrorist attacks on various stations. We don`t know yet what they want to achieve. But they seem to get along well with the usual criminal scum.\n\nThen we got hostile ships of Sith origin all around the galaxy. Nobody knows if they are just fanatics or even controlled by droids. But so far every attempt to communicate has failed. Historians from a very knowledgable era in the New Republic have established the theory that they come from an ancient automated Rakata factory called the Starforge. The only concern of this faction seems to expand and extract resources from entire planets to create copies of themselves.\n\nAll major corporations have formed a large association called THE CARTELL. They could strike a deal with everyone, even with these Sith! They leave them alone. The cartell got everyone by the balls because of that. Most supply lines are still too fragile and major factions depend too much on Cartell shipping services. This allowed them to enforce certain rules on the galaxy to ensure constant profits. With all that money they employ mercenary groups which we could also hire.\n\nCertain actions like scanning without a police license or destroying property that the Cartell has currently put under protectorate are forbidden and get punished with a fine![/justify]\n\n</t>
		<t id="1807">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]I got troubling news, boss.\n\nThe Star Forge has gone completely haywire. It must`ve overloaded its internal processing facilities. We should prepare for galaxy wide Sith invasions. Sectors with high abnormal signals seem to be most affected.\n\nYou must lead us through these dark times![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="1808">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Our science division just finished two prototype Jump Beacons! Our old ship based hyperdrives might have become useless, but we could effectively build a static hyperspace bridge between these portable devices!\n\nThe Rebel Alliance has a much more advanced version installed in their Outpost stations which works similar\nWe on the other hand have just entered this field of research. Before we start production we need to finish calibrating energy patterns for the prototype with very expensive and bulky lab equipment.\n\n\n\033YTo permanently unlock Jump Beacon construction we must first build an Outpost in any Hyperlane sector! The galaxy map shows you which sectors got this special trait.\n\n[/justify]
\n</t>
		<t id="1809">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Jump Beacon calibrations are complete! The two prototypes have been stored in our new Outpost. To construct more of these portable new devices we must build a special factory for jump cores and use them in the mobile factory module for capships. I recommend to upgrade our TL soon, boss.\n\n\n\033YFuture Jump Beacon producion is unlocked! Simply drop them in space and all your ships will automatically treat them just like normal warpgates!\n\n\33YTo have your personal playership plot an autopilot path via Jump Beacons you have to bind a special hotkey in the interface extensions section.\n\n\n\33WMayhem 3 veterans who want additional challenge can go in the t-file and enable an option which additionally restricts jump beacons to only work between Hyperlane sectors! Highly recommended if you like having to adapt your strategy and solve logistical problems.\n\n[/justify]
\n</t>
		<t id="1810">Midgame Quickstart</t>
		<t id="1811">[author]\033CMandalore the Gentle[/author]Friend of the Mandalorians! My heart carries great sadness. I must inform you that our great grand leader Mandalore the Ultimate has passed away unexpectetly!\n\nYours truly, Mandalore the Gentle, has succeeded him and took control of the Mandalorian people. Its my declared goal to end this violent bloodshed. The brass is hard to sway, but in time i will succeed. We must demilitarize and reforge our weapons into tools which benefit the well being of all living things. I hope that one day you can see this truth too.\n\n\n[yellow]!!! Strategy advice: !!![/yellow]\nOf course he is completely nuts. Both of you are at war against the galaxy and this will never change. And the Sith are coming too!\n\nYour Mandalorian allies might be very strong right now. But thanks to this fool they will now build their fleets much smaller and not replace all losses. They will also produce slower than before and consume more resources.\n\nWinning the Crusade might start to rest more and more on your shoulders.</t>
		<t id="2040">[author]\033GPoe Dameron[/author]Somehow palpatine will return again.</t>
		<t id="2041">[author]\033GNew Republic[/author]So who exactly is gonna stop the Yuuzhan Vong if they are arriving here too?</t>
		<t id="2042">[author]\033GSeparatist Council[/author]We surrender! Please don`t kill us. Lord Sidious promised us peace!</t>
		<t id="2043">[author]\033GLord Vader[/author]This is a glorious day! It has seen the end of Kenobi and this time also the end of the Rebellion.</t>
		<t id="2044">[author]\033GTHE Senate[/author]In order to ensure our security and continuing stability, the Republic will be reorganized into the first Galactic Empire, for a safe and secure society.</t>
		<t id="2045">[author]\033GMandalore the Ultimate[/author]You defeated us! Accept my surrender and take my mask. I am not worthy.</t>
		<t id="2050">[justify][author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Message to %s\nObject: IMPORTANT\nDate: %s\n\nYour ship gets pulled out of hyperspace. Leaving a fuzzy feeling in your stomach. Do you want to take a moment and answer some questions to customize your gamestart?\n\n\033WSome lags and stutters can appear in the first ten minutes of the game, even after galaxy generation.[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2053">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Did any ships from your convoy also make it through the anomaly?</t>
		<t id="2054">i can see the MINER vessel we hijacked on Kessel!</t>
		<t id="2055">an escort FIGHTER is still with me!</t>
		<t id="2056">seems like only a single HAULER survived!</t>
		<t id="2057">my TAXI shuttle survived! But the cantina band has stopped playing.</t>
		<t id="2058">bad luck. I`m the only one</t>
		<t id="2059">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Any money in your pockets?</t>
		<t id="2062">back on Rodia i gambled everything away in that pazaak den</t>
		<t id="2063">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]In the old world you`ve been leading a private organization in %s territory. But how would you describe your previous relations with the authority?</t>
		<t id="2067">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Are there still any construction plans saved on your shipcomputer?</t>
		<t id="2070">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]How successful was your initial sensor sweep. Could the ship connect to any satellites nearby?</t>
		<t id="2074">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Was your organization already a thing back in the Clone Wars and escorted a Separatist VIP?</t>
		<t id="2077">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Or did you smuggle bacta to a hidden Rebel base?</t>
		<t id="2080">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Was it still around after the Galactic Civil War and helped the New Republic?</t>
		<t id="2083">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Nah, i bet you actually like the Galactic Empire.</t>
		<t id="2086">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Should there be additional Sith in your galaxy?</t>
		<t id="2087">reduce them</t>
		<t id="2088">just keep it at normal level</t>
		<t id="2089">gimme more</t>
		<t id="2090">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Do you think that the corruption is a problem in the outer border galaxies?</t>
		<t id="2094">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Do you think that space exploration should be a priority?</t>
		<t id="2097">We should explore more to awake more vengeful Sith!</t>
		<t id="2098">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]How do you want to ascend and prove your worth as a leader?\n\n\033WFrom this screen, you can choose a Quickstart that will advance the main plot, immediately complete your Ascension and unlock the ability to conquer your first sector. It is [u]not recommended[/u] for new players.\n\n\033WCompleting your Ascension without Quickstart will reward you with 100,000 credits.\n
\n\033WMidgame Quickstart gives you everything you need for a healthy 4 sector player empire. A small military fleet with a capship, lots of freighters, miners, money, reputation, resources, blueprints, stations, and a special cheat TL which can load everything at once. This skips about 2-3 days of playtime \(most of the early game\) and lets you start more established. All your stations are still loaded up and you can choose your starting sectors \(once you've claimed your 4th sector, the SWM3 earlygame officially ends and the Mandalorians will arrive and cause more war\)</t>
		<t id="2103">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]Congratulations! Your personal database is now up to date. Would you like some general guidance?</t>
		<t id="2104">No, i`m good.</t>
		<t id="2105">What should i do now?</t>
		<t id="2107">[author]\033GGame Setup[/author]General Difficulty Setting</t>
		<t id="2200">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Glad you`re still with us, boss! \(Volkhart was a high ranking representative of your organization and your trusted right hand\)\n\nWe also got stranded, but that was six months ago! Damn, we could already tell you stories for sure. Me and a few survivors from our lost convoy could start a new life here. And we met folk from all around the galaxy! They told us that this happens quite often. People arriving time-shifted that is.\n\nWe don`t know where we are. Must be the remotest, strangest part of the Unknown Regions, but heck! I`m not even sure if we are still in our own galaxy! I got to know this loaded Twi-Lek guy who claims that he already took shots during the Great Galactic War. That was thousands of years ago! And you know what. After seeing all this i do believe him!\n\nSome say it was a failed experiment at the imperial research facility near the Maw. Others claim it was caused by a powerful Sith Holocron. Whatever it was. We are now stuck here. And apparently there is no hope to return. We have to look forward. Thanks to you we already clawed our way to the top back in the old world. You can do it again! We are no longer bound by the rules of the %s! There are countless lost souls in need of strong leadership. Once you prove that you can give them purpose again, they will follow you.\n\n\n\033WThe Ascension is a set of goals that you can follow in the dedicated section of your Personal console. Completing this quest will gather enough support to build a new empire![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2201">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Our team is currently trying to nail down your exact position. We should be able to give you a rendezvous station soon.[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2202">[justify][author]\033GVolkhart[/author]Boss,\n\nwe got a read on your ship. Give me a second\n...\n Operator! Inform safehouse 51! They are to prepare the meeting room! And tell their engineer to beginn installing the ITEM on the commander`s ship as soon as he arrives!\n...\nOk boss, we got a destination for you. Please dock to the station %s in the sector %s. I will upload the location to your personal journal.\n\nI`m looking forward to see you in person again.\n\n\033WYour personal journal differs from your message log. It can store custom entries and also automatically updates mission objectives. You can access your journal through your Personal console \(assign a hotkey or use the Additional Ship Command menu to open it\). You can also assign a hotkey directly to your journal.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2203">[justify]You did it! We have a TL waiting for you in %s. Unload the Outpost from the cargo bay in an empty sector to conquer it. This Outpost comes with some food and basic resources to get started. Be careful though, as factions that are in adjacent sectors won`t like the fact that you settle so close to them. For this first time they should not object, but the bigger your empire gets, the more you have to appease those neighboring factions before claiming new sectors.\n\n[white]Note that you can unload a station if you are in a different sector by using the Remote Drop Station command available in the Special section of your TL.\n[/white]\n[yellow]!!! SWM3 - please read this !!![/yellow]\nYour starting location can make the difference between a smooth buildup and a tough crawl. Your position on the galaxy map is actually much more important than any sector stats. You generally have two major options. Settling in an area which has many nearby empty sectors, or near friendly factions. Out of fear to not get enough sectors new players often choose vast empty areas and want to expand quickly. This decision often backfires because these areas contain many pirate bases and are typical travel routes for Sith patrols. Choosing a starting location which puts other factions in between you and Sith sectors or pirate bases makes your life much easier. Your neighbors will already take out most enemies before they even get to you and you can even depend on friendly police forces to come into your sector and help out. Buying the resources you so desperately need is also safe and quick if a lot of friendly factories are nearby.\n\nAreas with many empty sectors can almost always be left to claim later. There is a special mechanic which prevents major factions from expanding into unknown sectors. All factions combined are only allowed to claim roughly as many of these sectors as you already have during the playthrough. So you can expect to get a shot on roughly half of the unknown sectors which exist at gamestart. Although the exact number also depends on the expansion setting you selected during galaxy creation.\n\n[yellow]TLDR[/yellow]: you can`t be sure to get certain specific unknown sectors for yourself, but you can be sure that a certain amount always gets left for you to claim.\n\n\nSWM3 is focussing much more on the size of your empire. It is generally recommended to build your sectors up before you expand further. [green]Excessive[/green] land grabbing might trigger certain plot developments that you are not prepared for.[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2204">[justify]We have a TL waiting for you in %s. Unload the Outpost from the cargo bay in an empty sector to conquer it. This Outpost comes with some food and basic resources to get started. Be careful though, as factions that are in adjacent sectors won`t like the fact that you settle so close to them. For this first time they should not object, but the bigger your empire gets, the more you have to appease those neighboring factions before claiming new sectors.\n\n[white]Note that you can unload a station if you are in a different sector by using the Remote Drop Station command available in the Special section of your TL.\n[/white]\n[yellow]!!! SWM3 - please read this !!![/yellow]\nYour starting location can make the difference between a smooth buildup and a tough crawl. Your position on the galaxy map is actually much more important than any sector stats. You generally have two major options. Settling in an area which has many nearby empty sectors, or near friendly factions. Out of fear to not get enough sectors new players often choose vast empty areas and want to expand quickly. This decision often backfires because these areas contain many pirate bases and are typical travel routes for Sith patrols. Choosing a starting location which puts other factions in between you and Sith sectors or pirate bases makes your life much easier. Your neighbors will already take out most enemies before they even get to you and you can even depend on friendly police forces to come into your sector and help out. Buying the resources you so desperately need is also safe and quick if a lot of friendly factories are nearby.\n\nAreas with many empty sectors can almost always be left to claim later. There is a special mechanic which prevents major factions from expanding into unknown sectors. All factions combined are only allowed to claim roughly as many of these sectors as you already have during the playthrough. So you can expect to get a shot on roughly half of the unknown sectors which exist at gamestart. Although the exact number also depends on the expansion setting you selected during galaxy creation.\n\n[yellow]TLDR[/yellow]: you can`t be sure to get certain specific unknown sectors for yourself, but you can be sure that a certain amount always gets left for you to claim.\n\n\nSWM3 is focussing much more on the size of your empire. It is generally recommended to build your sectors up before you expand further. [green]Excessive[/green] land grabbing might trigger certain plot developments that you are not prepared for.\n[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2205">[justify]You don`t know who i am, but we know who you are.\n\n[/justify][left]Surely you noticed that your old hyperdrives don`t work around here. Everyone depends on these jumpgates to get around. Everyone? No, not at all. Mobility is a huge advantage of certain key figures. You would want to be one of them now wouldn`t you?\n\nI have a tool which can help you to go from a sector to another faster than almost anyone else in this galaxy. I`m willing to sell it to you for 100,000 credits. You won`t find this elsewhere. if you`re interested, come to %s with the money.\n\n[/left][justify]Why so cheap? You might be asking. Let`s just say that it would be in our shared best interest.\n[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2206">[justify][author]\033ONews Network[/author]Time of dispatch: %s\n\nThis morning, another group of Sith has been spotted in the sector %s, where they are gathering to destroy our assets. This old network is already being hacked by government entities to try to cut us off from telling the truth. We must act now and stop our internal wars in order to face the Sith and the Star Forge which is responsible for their creation. This will probably be the last and only message we`ll be able to send. We need help to destroy the Sith [u]stations[/u] in the hope of slowing them down and maybe even stopping them completely.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2207">[justify][author]\033GBreaking News[/author]Dear citizens,\n\nDespite efforts to end the wars and bring peace in our galaxy, the ruthless mandalorian group of Death Watch conducted terrorist attacks and recently sabotaged several of our stations. These actions will not be tolerated and we will find and put on trial any person related to those crimes.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2208">[justify][author]\033GAutomatic Delivery System[/author]Hello %s,\n\nYou have \033C{2}\033X objects waiting for you. You can only unlock one. To unlock, pay %s credits.\n\n\033WThe choice you`re about to make is irreversible. The Jumpdrive Prototype allows your own ship to teleport to any sector for a variable amount of Energy Cells. It has a long cooldown. On the other hand, the Experimental Transporter Device allows you, as a pilot, to teleport to any of your ship and switch place with its pilot. It doesn`t cost anything and has a much shorter cooldown. Both devices are activated with the Teleportation device hotkey, and they cannot be used to transport anything else than your ship or yourself.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2211">[justify][author]\033GAutomatic Delivery System[/author]One message enclosed:\n===================\n\nI cannot really meet you in person, it would be too dangerous. The device you just acquired is said to be impossible to duplicate. I hope it will help you nonetheless, and that you will bring peace to our galaxy.\n\nGood luck![/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2212">[justify][author]\033ONews Network[/author]Time of dispatch: %s\n\nWe have just intercepted several official reports confirming the loss of Sith station signals in all their sectors. Those reports are quite incomplete and somewhat cryptic in some sections, so we are not sure if the Sith are not hiding in deep space. But for now, let`s just thank the Independent for what he has done, and hope that the Sith won`t return.\n\n\033WYou have gained some reputation with all factions, plus one Favor point.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2213">[justify]Maybe you should take a look on the galaxy map. He just repainted it quite a bit. If he truly is a puppet master for criminals we might want to avoid any areas he has just taken over. Consider to put this entire mandalorian faction on the blacklist. And maybe additional sectors at their borders if they are inside our worker range. Just to keep your freighters safe. At least until the dust has settled.[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2219">[justify][author]\033GBreaking News[/author]Dear citizens!\n\nIt`s a great day today, as the Sith portals have all just vanished from our galaxy! Our scientists are still not able to explain this phenomenon, nor deny if whether or not it is permanent, but they seem to be rather confident and full of hope for our future. They`ve also managed to extract precious data from the Sith ships.\n\n\033WCongratulations, you have defeated the Sith in this galaxy! As a reward, you can now research all Sith ships.[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2225">[justify][author]\033MThe Cartell[/author]Dear pilot,\n\nYou have been authorized to participate in the expansion of this universe! The recent registration of your ship will let you trade, fight and expand in your outer border galaxy. You`ve chosen to be an independent and as such, you have a special role to play. Your task will be harder and you will have less support than other factions, but if you manage to build a respectable empire, the Cartell and all its subsidiaries could entrust you with the important mission of terraforming new planets. But for now, we`ll monitor all your actions and we`ll contact you again if you are worth of our attention.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2226">[justify][author]\033MThe Cartell[/author]Dear pilot,\n\nIn the light of recent events, we have decided to speed things up. It is now time to discuss your future among the galaxy.\n\nWe are now giving you the ability to order a terraforming mission on the planets you control. Once an order has been given, our terraformers will teleport there and start the process. During this time, the ancient Star Forge could be awaken and will probably attack the sector. Hold tight, defend your assets and keep an eye on the abnormal signals displayed on your galaxy map. These signals can be used to encrypt transmissions. They may be a good indication of how strong the Star Forge can respond in the sector. Also, if the signals are low, we will be able to terraform the planet faster.\n\nWe want you to terraform %s planets. Do that, and we may be able to help your little empire.\n\n\033WYou can access the terraforming menu through the Sectors section of the Ministry Of War.\n\n\033WFinishing this mission will certainly cause a long lasting response from the ancient Star Forge. Be prepared. Though in SWM3 these attacks are much weaker. They are less of an existential threat to the galaxy and more a disruption for the factions. So don`t be afraid either.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2227">[justify][author]\033MThe Cartell[/author]Dear pilot,\n\nYou have done a great job helping us terraforming your planets. Unfortunately, the Star Forge is too much of a threat in this area for us to invest more time into your installations. We leave you a team of specialists in case you would like to terraform more planets. Good luck.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2232">[justify][author]\033GBreaking News[/author]Dear citizens,\n\nmedia outlets are reporting an insurrection, orchestrated by the ruthless Death Watch. The Mandalorians, suspected to run multiple criminal organizations from the shadows, just conquered different sectors in the whole galaxy, giving them a strong power in these days of suffering. We don`t know their objectives yet, but given their cruel history everyone should be ready for more war.\n\nGovernment officials from all major factions have expressed their concerns about the small independent empire which was just recently established in the border region, and which hasn't yet taken any diplomatic stance in the matter.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2500">[justify][author]\033GCartell Harmony Department[/author]Message to %s\nObject: Legal notification\nDate: %s\n\nDear Sir/Madam,\n\nIt has been reported to our service that one of your ships has taken part into the destruction of an asset legally protected by a Protectorate treaty. We`d like to remind you that such action is illegal in all sectors. The Cartell has been mandated to collect from you the penalty of %s credits.\n\nThis is an automated message, please do not reply.\nThe amount of your penalty has already been debited from all your accounts.\nThank you for your cooperation.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2502">[justify][author]\033R%s-Encrypted Transmission[/author]Dear leader,\n\nMy name is %s and I work for the %s. After conquering the sector %s you shall henceforth be called the Independent.\nMy government likes to congratulate to your success. We`d like to help you developping your little empire and put some pressure on your new neighbors. So if you need a favor, just ask, i know the right persons.\n\nBut don`t get cocky! We prefer to have allies without too much ambition.\n\n\033WYou have just gained 1 Favor point from the %ss. These points are used to take diplomatic actions from the Ministry of War menu.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2503">[justify][author]\033G%s[/author]We would like to thank you for joining us into the war against the %s. Our empire is getting stronger every day and with your help, we will be able to neutralize this foe. I will speak of you to some of our teams to let them help you if you need any assistance. Good luck in your fight!\n\n\033WYou are now in permanent war with the %s and you have earned 1 Favor point from the %s. These points are used to take diplomatic actions from the Ministry of War menu that you can access through your Personal console or by assigning a hotkey.[/justify]\n</t>
		<t id="2510">[author]\033R%s War Cabinet[/author]Dear Independent leader,\n\nDespite our poor relation and our recent armed conflicts, we would like to show you how merciful our people are, and offer you a truce that would erase our past quarrels... Would you accept?\n</t>
		<t id="2511">Commander,\n\nAnother half day has passed. Here is our regular report:\n\nWe own %s{0} sectors, %s{1} stations and %s{2} ships. On average, the other factions own %s{3} sectors, %s{4} stations and %s{5} ships.\n\nThe total strength of our fleet is evaluated at a score of %s{6}. On average, the other factions have a score of %s{7}.\n\nThe Sith have %s{13} ships and %s{14} stations. The Pirates have %s{15} ships and %s{16} stations.\n\nWe have the following products in high quantity: %s{8}.\n\nWe have a total of %s{9} credits.\n\nWe are monitoring %s{10} out of %s{11} sectors.\n\nOur fleet has an average maintenance factor of %s{12} %.\n\nEnd of the report.\n</t>
		<t id="2600">[justify]We have reasons to believe that the Sith are going to invade the sector of %s. If you accept the mission, you will be paid for each Sith killed by you or any of your ships.\n\nDifficulty: %s\nCredits reward: per kill\nReputation reward: per kill\n\n[white]Sith appear when your own ship or any of your fleet leaders enters the sector.\n\nThis mission scales to your Fight rank.[/white]\n[/justify]</t>
		<t id="2619">[justify]Some Sith Interceptors keep attacking our miners in %s. One of our ships has recently been damaged, and we assume that the crew died in the battle. However, if you capture it and stay there for a time, the Khaaks will return and you can destroy them once and for all. If you succeed, you can keep the ship.\n\nDifficulty: %s\nCredits reward: per kill\nReputation reward: per kill\n\n[/justify][left]\033WThis mission scales to the strength of the ships you have in the sector of the miner ship once captured.\033X\n[/left]</t>
		<t id="2620">[justify]We are receiving strong Sith signals coming from the %s. We need someone to protect our station and destroy the beacon where they`re all coming from!\n\nDifficulty: %s\nCredits reward: per kill \053 %s\nReputation reward: per kill \053 %s\n\n[/justify][left]\033WThis mission scales to the strength of the ships you currently have in the sector of this station.\033X\n[/left]</t>
		<t id="2704">Captain, our IT team has identified a virus that is rapidly spreading through all our systems. The code has the signature of the Sith and we think that the main targets are our ships. We should stop all ship production until this problem is fixed. Fortunately, all previous ships built from our Outpost are safe.\n</t>
	</page>

	<page id="350037" title="Encyclopedia Texts" descr="0" voice="no">
		<t id="62">Mayhem Help</t>
		<t id="63">Galaxy</t>
		<t id="64">Empire and Warfare</t> <!-- History -->
		<t id="65">Mechanics</t> <!-- Information -->
		<t id="66">Star Wars Mayhem 3</t> <!-- Stories -->
	</page>

	<page id="9974" title="Mayhem Encyclopedia Custom Articles">

		<!-- Galaxy -->
		<t id="1">Background Story</t>
		<t id="2">Just recently factions from different timelines got stranded in an unknown part of the Star Wars galaxy. They begin to realize that they'll have to fight for valuable resources. Everyone wants to play into his unique strengths.\n\nYou start your journey as a fallen leader of a large organization. Its up to you whether your group was driven by economics or ideals.\n\nMegacorporations have banded together and formed the influencial CARTELL to ensure their constant profits by enforcing certain rules of warfare on everybody.\n\nRight now you have lost most of your assets. But your renown and previous leadership experience will help you to quickly rise to power once again!</t>
		<t id="3">Sector Stats</t>
		<t id="4">Each sector has different statistics:\n\nPopulation: the maximum amount of people the Outpost can have.\n\nResearch rate: the speed at which your Research station will operate.\n\nStation support: the maximum allowed number of stations. This includes all docks and factories.\n\nDejure owner: for whatever reason this faction permanently wants to get all these sectors under their control and will invade them in priority.\n\nCompany: if a company is assigned to a safe sector, a Trading station will appear. This station trades various wares that depends on the company.\n\nAbnormal signals: some dangerous threats could be more interested in sectors that have a stronger signal.\n\nHyperlane: these sectors are related to unlocking hyperjump technology.\n\nOutpost production and consumption: each Outpost produces a type of food, and consumes another one. The selection of this food depends on the sector.\n\n\nSWM3:\nFor Star Wars in particular you might want to start in sectors which have high factory support. Everything in this mod revolves about the size of your empire. And the amount of factories will be your main progression. So the more stations you can support before having to expand into more sectors and getting closer to the next plot stage, the better.</t>
		<t id="5">Economy</t>
		<t id="6">The number of different resources, their costs and prices have been greatly reduced compared to other X3 mods.\n\nBecause everything is now focused on crafting, every resource you see being transported can be used by either an Outpost to craft ships and stations, or by a factory to manufacture a higher tier product.\n\nAlmost every ship in the universe must be created in an Outpost.\n\nThe AI cares about what resources it needs. Thats why there are additional trade rules which might confuse new players.\nFor example a faction Outpost is not willing to sell its entire Hull Plating to you. They only do that if they already have enough to satisfy their ship building desires.\nAnd on the contrary they also won't buy an unlimited amount of the same resource from you. And while they don't actually have to stick to a money budget, they still won't spend it needlessly. They just want to get enough resources to keep their factions working! Keep this in mind and check actual demand before you commit into producing something. Selling large quantities of, lets say Energy Cells, might work initially when the economy needs to start, but its usually not sustainable!</t>
		<t id="7">Factions</t>
		<t id="8">There are five main factions which drive the core gameplay. Galactic Empire, New Republic, Separatist CIS, Rebel Alliance and Republic. Later there will also be the Mandalorians. They all consume resources and use similar types of fleets to fight for more sectors. For more information about that, see both, the Invasions and Squadrons sections.\n\nSecondary factions work different and get all their ships for free at a certain rate. These include the Sith Terraformers, the Pirates and the neutral corporations of the Cartell.\n\nIf you're coming from LU, note that the Phanon Corporation no longer exists. And that the OCV does not follow any of the past LU rules.</t>
		<t id="9">Missions</t>
		<t id="10">Vanilla missions have been replaced by a new system. There are 12 procedural missions:\n\nPatrol \(fight\): hunt Sith fleets in a given sector. The Sith will only appear when your own ship or any of your fleet leaders enters the sector. Each kill will grant you some credits and reputation, but you won't receive any if you just wait for other ships to do your job.\n\nSuppression \(fight\): factions are often at war against each other. This mission asks you to destroy existing ships of an enemy faction. The factions against whom you are in permanent war will be prioritized.\n\nBait \(fight\): capture a nearby abandoned miner ship to attract Kha'ak ships from deep space. Each kill will grant you some credits and reputation, and you will get the ship if you succeed in protecting it.\n\nDefense \(fight\): the Sith have built a jump beacon nearby and they are targetting a station. Protect the station and destroy the beacon.\n\nProvision \(trade\): a station needs various wares. You can deliver them with any of your ships. The reward is always based on the average price of all wares.\n\nAcquisition \(trade\): sometimes the AI will send his Tugs to capture abandoned ships. These ships can be used in their Outposts when needed, or sold to you through these missions.\n\nDeliveries \(trade\): a shady character will ask you to do multiple deliveries. Make sure you can defend yourself, as the parcels you ought to deliver are valuable to some pirates.\n\nProspecting \(think\): some asteroids need to be scanned in a given sector. If you've already scan all existing asteroids in this sector, new ones will be created.\n\nCollection \(think\): Artefacts have been dropped around a given sector. You must find them and bring them back to the station that gave you the mission. Artefacts come in a flying ware that the AI cannot loot.\n\nExploration \(think\): deploy Advanced satellites at given coordinates. An error margin of 5 km is allowed. Note that there is a command to move to coordinates in the Navigation section.\n\nRescue \(think\): capture an abandoned ship and get it back to its station, with all passengers alive onboard. As a reward, you can keep the ship.\n\nPolice \(think\): find a criminal and bring him to justice. As a reward, you can keep his ship.\n\nUnlike vanilla missions, you have to dock to the station to see the mission briefing and accept the offer, or abandon a mission you previously accepted. You can also use the Mission Briefing command that is available in the Additional Ship Commands section of the ship console. With that command, it is possible to accept a mission from any of your ships. Note that missions are generated when you enter a new sector and that they do not have a time limit.</t>
		<t id="11">Outposts</t>
		<t id="12">Outposts are the central stations of every main faction, including yours. They serve as local headquarters and also as factories with their ability to build ships, lasers, missiles and shields. They are crucial in your development, because they represent the only way you have to build stations and ships.\n\nOutposts do not work magically. People live inside and work together to manufacture everything you need. In exchange, you must provide them with food if you do not want them to starve to death. Each Outpost produces a certain type of food and consumes another one, depending on the sector \(see the Sectors Stats section\). The consumption can be removed with the perk No Food Consumption.\n\nPeople can work on multiple projects at the same time without any penalty.\n\nOutposts can be affected by various events that will have unfortunate effects. The more people you have, the more chance you get of generating an event. You can restrict the maximum number of people in each of your Outpost through the Administration menu and lower the risk or food consumption during early game. You can also avoid these events with the perk Insurance Policy.\n\nOnly automated Trader Workers and ships that run a Trade Run command can dock to NPC Outposts. This is so that the trade restrictions are always respected and the player can't steal resources they shouldn't want to sell.</t>
		<t id="13">Neutral Companies</t>
		<t id="14">Companies are minor factions that stand neutral in the many wars that are fought over the galaxy. They have their own Trading stations and trade in different wares, depending on the company.\n\nThey have powerful Traders which can survive any hostilities, because the Cartell negotiated non-aggression pacts with everyone, including the Pirates and the Sith!\n\nThe Cartell also employs mercenaries to hire or smuggle contraband.\n\nCompanies are always sector-based and will only build their local Trading Station when the sector is safe, ie. not Unknown and not Sith. Any sector you own is also considered safe.\n\nDestroying company assets is highly illegal and gets punished with a heavy fine from the Cartell.</t>
		
		<!-- Empire and Warfare -->
		<t id="1001">Expansion</t>
		<t id="1002">The general rule to expand your own empire is that you only need to unload an Outpost or a factory into an empty sector to conquer it. However, to expand into already occupied territories, you first need to destroy all faction stations that are not owned by a company. Besides, capturing a new sector will cost you some reputation with adjacent owners \(except for the first one\).\n\nThrough your Personal console, you can abandon a sector you already own, or give it to another faction if your reputation is high enough.\n\nOther factions will not conquer any unknown sectors before you first capture one yourself. Then they  must follow a rule of the Cartell which mandates them to, in total, only claim as many sectors as you already have claimed*. The only exception to this rule is in galaxies where the expansion has been set to "none"; in that case the other factions won't limit their initial expansion.\n\nDon't be too eager to conquer new sectors! Each of them can draw the attention of Sith or Pirates, and you better have enough firepower to defend your existing assets before going deeper into unknown territory.\n\n*This can be changed in the customizable 9972 t-file, id 251.</t>
		<t id="1003">Manufacture</t>
		<t id="1004">Crafting is one of the most important features of Mayhem. Ships, stations, shields, lasers, missiles and equipment can be crafted with various resources that you can all produce by building factories in your sectors. In Mayhem, Saturn Complex Hubs and Vanilla Complexes have been deactivated, but the costs of many things have been reduced to keep the game balanced.\n\nAll crafting costs are based on the average price of the product you're trying to make and if different resources are used, then they're always required in equal amounts.\n\nEach Outpost has its own specialization levels in different areas. The more projects you complete in a specific area \(ship, laser, missile, shield or station\) the better you become at it. By default, this bonus can go from 0% to 50%; that means that both resource and time costs will be reduced by this percentage.\nNote that new AI outposts always start already levelled up and their maximum specialization will even increase in later stages of your playthrough.\n\nCancelling a project will always give you back the resources you've invested.\n\nCrafting a ship also requires people. And people regrow slower when the population is closer to its maximum.</t>
		<t id="1005">Workers</t>
		<t id="1006">Workers are automated ships that are used to run your empire. Each Outpost, and certain factories, have a limited number of slots to assign different types of Workers. You can see this in the Administration tab of your Outposts. Every Worker respects the "Max. sector distance for all Workers" setting of his station.\n\nAgents: they operate either an Outpost or a factory. Based on an outpost they will look for a job from the jobs list you define in the Logistics menu of the Outpost manager. If affected to a factory, they will look to import resources and export products to any of your other stations. Unlike Traders, Agents never trade with stations that you do not own. All Agents and all Traders from all factions are synchronized with each other and don't go if another ship already wants to load or unload the same ware at that station.\n\nExplorers: their only goal is to make sure that every reachable sector is monitored by an Advanced Satellite. If they can't find an Advanced Satellite from your own stations, they will wait until they do. They won't buy Satellites from other stations.\n\nLooters: they look for abandoned wares in all reachable sectors and bring them back to their homebase.\n\nMiners: they will mine the debris in the sector and unload their cargo to their homebase when full. Mobile mining fleets no longer exist. Only Ore and Silicon Wafers can be mined, as well as coloured crystals and minerals, that can be sold or used to craft equipment through your Outposts' hangars.\n\nTraders: ST and UT don't exist any more. Outpost Traders are the only Workers that can interact with factories from another faction. Foreign Traders can only come to your stations if you explicitly allow them to. Keep in mind that if an AI Trader buys from you, he might sell it straight to your enemies afterwards!\n\nTugs: they look for abandoned ships in all reachable sectors and bring them back to their homebase. Some mission ships or other special ships, such as the ones that emit a remnant signal, cannot be captured by Tugs.\n\nThe AI uses the exact same Workers as you, powered by the same scripts.\n\n\nFor performance reasons, Agents and Traders will never go further than 8 sectors. Jump beacons do not affect this range.</t>
		<t id="1007">Logistics</t>
		<t id="1008">There are two main screens that will help you to manage your logistics: the Agents menu and the Traders menu. Both are found in the Logistics tab of the Outpost manager. It's important to note that Agents only manage your own stations and never exchange money. Traders can interact with everything but always need to exchange money.\nThe wares that Traders are allowed to exchange from and to your Outposts must be manually added to the Traders list. Factories simply trade their product and resources according to their import-export thresholds that you can set in their Station parameters menu. Agents and Traders will always check these thresholds: a first time before going there, and a second time on arrival \(export only\). Each Outpost and each factory can be configured to accept or forbid either your Traders or AI's Traders.\n\nWhen an AI Trader comes to one of your stations, he can buy products or sell resources. If the station doesn't have enough money to buy all wares from a Trader, you will be notified \(your main account will NOT be debited\). Note that the AI will not trade at any price; its tolerance to unfair price is based on your trade rank. Fortunately there is an Automatic Pricing setting in all your factories. It is recommended to leave it on but never activate it on Outposts.\n\nAll Traders are synchronized and "lock" the station they're heading to, thus avoiding multiple Traders going to the same place for the same ware.\n\nEach station has a very important setting: "Max. sector distance for all Workers". This defines the range at which your Agents and Traders will look for trading partners. Note that the "Reachable factories" Agent job setting depends on that parameter as well.\n\nStation parameters can be modified either through the vanilla menu, or the useful Station settings menu in your Personal console. That can also setup an automatic credit transfer.</t>
		<t id="1009">Research</t>
		<t id="1010">The only way to acquire sufficient numbers of ships is to craft them with resources. However, to do that, you must first get the blueprint, listed in all Research stations, and in the Blueprints menu of your Personal console.\n\nThe Data Scanner allows you to unlock basic blueprints like for M4, M3, TS or maybe M6 during early game. Assign the hotkey and get into range. Scanning a ship is free and safe, but only unlocks a small part of the Blueprint of bigger ships.\n\nThe main way to unlock blueprints are Research stations. Given time they will unlock any ship blueprint. Each sector has a different research rate, so you might want to build them in the best sectors. Note that each project can be interrupted and resumed at any time. Research stations do not depend on people.\n\nSWM3 adds a global research discount which reduces all project costs. It gets increased by completing research projects and will make it faster to unlock more alternative ship designs. This is mostly for cosmetic reasons to make it easy for you to diversify your fleet in the later stages or convert more research stations into hacking stations. Researching your first few capships will still take almost as long as before.</t>
		<t id="1011">Maintenance</t>
		<t id="1012">In your Personal console, you'll see a Maintenance menu. It's very important that you keep an eye on this, because ship maintenance can get out of control. Military ships have a maintenance cost that increases over time if the ship remains undocked and travelling through space. That means that your ships are getting old and at some point you might want to consider recycle and rebuild them to lower your maintenance fees.\n\nAlternatively you can dock them to an Outpost with the Dry Dock perk. This will slowly undo the permanent cost increase and also makes the current costs entirely free.\n\nMobile Maintenance Kits ensure that the maintenance factor will always stay at 100%. But they are not really worth putting on smaller or medium ships.</t>
		<t id="1013">Marines</t>
		<t id="1014">Boarding has been totally removed in Mayhem 3. It can be reactivated in the 9972 t-file but it is not recommended and has the potential to corrupt your savegame permanently.</t>
		<t id="1015">Faction Relations</t>
		<t id="1016">The galaxy being a very dynamic place, faction relations are dynamic as well. Here are the rules:\n\n1. Factions are "neutral" when they have no invasion in progress, or if they signed a truce with each other. A truce can be signed after a faction conquers a sector and if there are no more invasions in progress. As the name suggests, it's very temporary.\n\n2. Factions are "friend" if they have an unbreakable alliance, or a coalition.\n\n3. Factions are "foe" when an invasion is in progress or if they have a total or a permanent war.\n\nUnbreakable alliances and total wars are bound to the galaxy and set during galaxy creation. Those last forever. Permanent wars are player-side only. A permanent war can either be bound to a total war, or declared at any time by the player, to any faction. Declaring a permanent war against another faction will grant you 1 Favor point and 1 maximum perk for all your present and future Outposts.</t>
		<t id="1017">Invasions</t>
		<t id="1018">Invasions between other factions follow some strict rules:\n\nA faction cannot claim Protectorates or an already claimed sector. They also cannot claim the original Sith sectors and will avoid claiming too many unknown sectors when they can.\n\nClaims have a duration, at the end of which the invader will generally retreat.\n\nNewly conquered sector get declared as Protectorates by the Cartell. This lasts a few hours to rebuild the economy and relief the area from further destruction.\n\nBattle Groups are the AI fleet type that initiates an invasion. However, they can be reinforced by other fleets, such as Task Forces or Border Patrols.\n\nA sector is conquered by the claimer when all stations are destroyed. Company stations are ignored.\n\nYou, as player, automatically claim a sector when you destroy a station.\n\nDestroying a Protectorate station is generally not worth it because it will provoke a very high reputation penalty from all factions and a fine from the Cartell.\n\nIt is possible to completely annihilate a faction, but usually only you as the player can do that.</t>
		<t id="1019">Squadrons</t>
		<t id="1020">To defend their territories, invade new sectors and harass the enemy, the main factions have several fleets of different types:\n\nBattle Group: used to invade new sectors. They generally tend to regroup to a safe location before claiming the sector they want to conquer, then move towards it.\n\nBorder Patrol: used to defend border sectors, giving priority to "hot sectors" \(see below\).\n\nEscort: often escort civilian ships \(Workers\), otherwise they defend their current sector.\n\nPolice: chase ships that have illegal wares onboard and they also attack hostile ships that are in adjacent sectors. By default, they defend their current sector.\n\nRearguard: work the exact same way as Border Patrols, except that they focus on non-border sectors.\n\nTask Force: the most aggressive fleet. They can go in enemy territory to attack random ships. However, their priority is to destroy enemy satellites and jump beacons, as well as assisting Battle Groups.\n\nWhen combat happens the sector triggers an alert and gets marked as a "Hot" sector. Such sectors will always receive a special attention from most fleets. The response time can be different between factions. For example the Rebel Alliance can respond vastly quicker and in with many fleets at once due to their secret hyperlane jump network.\n\nMost fleets will retreat when they feel overwhelmed. If that happens, they will go to the nearest safe Outpost and wait for reinforcements.</t>
		<t id="1021">Missiles</t>
		<t id="1022">Missiles have gone through a complete overhaul. The main idea is to reduce the confusion that exists between all the different types of missiles, and also to modify the vanilla gameplay by sticking a bit more to a believable model.\n\nThe first major change concerns the classification of missiles. You have three categories:\n\n- Fox 1: Semi active radar homing. These missiles are not heatseeker and require a locked target to be fired. They are rather slow and have a medium range. Fox 1 missiles can only be identified by CCDS MK1. The identification process can be done at high range and is mandatory for a chaff to be fired at the incoming missile.\n- Fox 2: Infrared. These missiles are heatseeker \(they can lock a missile instead of a ship\) and do not require a lock. They are fast and have a short range, but due to their nature, they can miss targets that have small heat signature such as fighters. Fox 2 missiles can only be identified by CCDS MK2, at medium range.\n- Fox 3: Active radar homing. These missiles are not heatseeker and do not require a lock. They have an optimal speed and a high range. Fox 3 missiles can only be identified by CCDS MK3, at short range.\n- Artillery missiles: Passive radar homing. These missiles can only be fired by M7M. They have the highest speed, the highest range, the highest damage and the highest price. Considering their wild nature, it is not possible to intercept artillery missiles with CCDS and chaffs. Like all other missiles however, they can be destroyed by laser fires, even though all missiles are a lot more resistant than in vanilla.\n\nAll missiles are racialized and every race has one of each type of missile.\n\nThe AI has been improved to fire missiles in the most efficient way possible, and also to keep good game performance and balanced gameplay. Therefore, the AI does not use missiles when out of sector \(your ships can\), and not against small fighters. The AI uses M8, and can also use M7M. These ships can always fire in Out-Of-Sector combat, like all of your ships. Each M8 has all CCDS built-in and can protect nearby allies.\n\nFighters cannot fire missiles. The only ship classes that can are M1, M2, M6, M7, M7M and M8. Artillery missiles can only be fired by M7M, while Fox missiles can be fired by all other classes.\n\nThere is no hotkey to manually fire a chaff. That's because CCDS have an extremely low chance of missing, and that you, as a human, cannot beat a radar.</t>
		<t id="1023">Hacking</t>
		<t id="1024">Hacking is a sneaky way to manipulate individual ships or steal lots of money from the owner.\n\nYou can partially disarm or damage the target. Shut down its shields, force it to retreat to a different sector, or even kill off the crew.\n\nAll ships have subsystems which are attached to a specific port. You can upload a virus from one of your hacking stations to target a specific port and its subsystem.\n\nFirst you need to uncover ports by scanning a ship with the hacking rootkit equipment. Scanning ships will mark them with a small dot in front of their name on the map.\nAll ships of the same type share the same port numbers, but each individual ship will have different ports opened or closed. Closed ports cannot be hacked.\nTo make a port vulnerable for a hack you need to research the port in a hacking station. This permanently unlocks it on all ships of the same type.\n\nNow you can use the rootkit again and install backdoors into the port. This consumes a hackerchip which can be crafted using the mobile factory equipment. Ships with backdoors are marked with a colored leading dot in the name and are part of your botnet. Virus upload is now possible at any time. A certain amount of botnet ships might be required for more powerful hacks and increased upload range requires other botnet ships in range to act as relays.\n\nEach hack has a certain risk to be detected. Possible consequences are retaliation hacks against your own ships or patching the port. Patched ports are permanently disabled. So for each Mayhem 3 playthrough and for each type of ship and subsystem you can only launch a limited amount of hacks. Eventually the ports will get patched.\n\n\nTips:\n\nTo draw the most benefit from this system you'll need a large botnet.\n\nInstalling a backdoor must not mean that you intend to hack a ship. Especially since you can loose all ships of the same type from your botnet if a hack gets detected\n\nYou can maintain a large botnet by installing backdoors into ships which are safe from physical destruction. Targets located deep inside a factions territory without pirate bases or Sith are usually a good idea. If there is no war nearby the ships will survive very long and enable powerful hacks against other targets.\n\nIf you just want to increase your botnet size you should target mining ships since they will always stay in a single sector. supply agents, civilian service ships and Rearguard Squadrons are also ok, as they will often at least somewhat stay in their factions territory and away from fights.\n\nTraders are less useful as their job is to travel between different factions and those can go to war at any time. Battlegroups, Task Forces, Police and Border Patrols are naturally bad choices because they actively seek trouble and get destroyed more frequently.</t>
		
		<!-- Mechanics -->
		<t id="2001">Ship Formations</t>
		<t id="2002">In Mayhem 3, all combat scripts have been rewritten from scratch. That means that some basic things have been redesigned. In that regard, combat tactics and ship formations have been overhauled. All formations, squadrons and fleets now have the same rules:\n\n1. The leader is at the center of the formation and only the leader runs the main script that tells him what to do in what situations.\n\n2. Followers are all the other ships that follow the leader and assist him. They will always try to protect the leader in priority, then attack his target, or assist other followers.\n\n3. Support ships are fighters that can be carried by a follower. As soon as they are in the carrier, and while the carrier is alive, they become independent from the formation. Their priority then becomes the protection and the assistance of the carrier. If the carrier dies, they will join the formation back, as standard followers. If the carrier is equipped with a Carrier Repair Module, the support ships will wait there while their hull is damaged.\n\nNote that wings are one of the few things - with turret scripts - that have been left untouched. Please report any problem you might encounter with them.</t>
		<t id="2003">Loot And Bailing Rate</t>
		<t id="2004">Loot, aka FLC for Fight Loot Chance is a Litcube's Universe feature that determines how much chance a ship has to drop shields and lasers if he's destroyed by a player's ship. However, in Mayhem, the FLC is a fixed rate that applies to every ship in the universe, including yours. The FLC level that you can see in the Pilot Status screen can be ignored. Freighters are special regarding loot. If they have a cargo, they will always drop a part of it, whoever destroys them.\n\nBailing rates in Mayhem have been decreased a lot. Abandoned ships are now limited in number, and Mayhem has its own bailing system.</t>
		<t id="2005">Personal Console</t>
		<t id="2006">Several hotkeys are crucial to the gameplay of Mayhem. The Personal console is by far the menu you will use the most. You can access it through a hotkey or through the Additional ship commands menu of your ships. Note that all custom hotkeys are deactivated when you are docked \(hardcoded limitation\).</t>
		<t id="2007">Gameplay Customization</t>
		<t id="2008">Many gameplay variables can be changed via a simple file: X3/addon/t/9972-L044.xml. Almost everything can be adjusted to your taste! This file is often referenced as "the t-file".\n\nStar Wars Mayhem 3 has its own t-file 9973-L044 with additional settings.</t>
		<t id="2009">Repair</t>
		<t id="2010">All ships are repaired over time for free when they are docked at any of your Outposts. They can also be repaired in a carrier if it's equipped with a Carrier Repair Module. However, the process is slower than in an Outpost.\n\nStations automatically repair themselves over time.</t>
		<t id="2011">New Equipment</t>
		<t id="2012">Lots of equipment are now included by default into all ships. However, for some of them like the Docking Computer and the Transporter Device, you will need to go through the Update ship menu from your Outpost's Hangar, and spend some coloured crystals to acquire them. These crystals come from mining, but they can also be transmuted from "normal" Crystals, ie. those produced in Crystal Fabs.\n\nPlease consult the Ship Equipment section of the encyclopedia to learn more about all the new equipments.</t>
		<t id="2013">Pirates</t>
		<t id="2014">Pirates have always been hiding in the darkest corners of the universe. Pirate bases can be randomly found in unknown sectors. They will create fighters and corvettes that will hunt down freighters and their precious cargo. You have to be careful about them, because the more territory you control, the more aggressive they'll get.\n\nPirate bases never respawn. You can dock to any Pirate base at anytime, even if they appear hostile. If you want to fix a bad reputation with a faction, you should dock to one of them.\n\nWhen a pirate kills a freighter the Cartell puts a bounty on his head. Hunting them with automated fleets can be a very lucrative way to earn money and also get reputation with the sector owner.\nBut eventually you want to get rid of these guys. The default way is to destroy all pirate respawn locations. Afterwards they will be gone. But the Mandalorians also offer a quest reward which completely stops them.</t>
		<t id="2015">Jump Beacons</t>
		<t id="2016">While the Rebel Alliance has advanced jump technology on all its Outpost stations, you are the only faction that is able to craft and use portable Jump Beacons. To do so, you first have to complete the Hyperlane studies quest after your Ascension. Then build a Jumpdrive Core Factory, and then use these cores in the Mobile Factory Kit.\n\nThe Beacons act like warpgates: once two beacons are in place, your ships will automatically start using them and will always try to find the shortest path between their location and their destination. For performance reasons, Jump Beacons do not affect the 'Max. sector distance' range setting of your stations.\n\nThe playership autopilot only respects jumpbeacons with a special hotkey you can set in the Interface Extensions section at the bottom.\n\nMayhem 3 veterans can use an option in the 9973 t-file to limit their jump beacons to Hyperlane sectors. This is very challenging.</t>
		<t id="2017">Sith</t>
		<t id="2018">Sith have some heavily defended sectors, and they regularly spawn invasion fleets. However, the defenders will not be reinforced over time. They're not rebuilt once destroyed.\n\nSpecial Sith raids will look for a way to strike deeper into your territory, instead of spawning from their stations.</t>
		<t id="2019">Difficulty</t>
		<t id="2020">You can only choose the difficulty setting of your game when you start it, through the initial survey. This setting affects the strength of Sith invasions, the number of Sith stations per sector \(hence the strength of defensive forces\), the strength of wandering Sith fleets that you can find in Unknown sectors, the number of pirates that are spawned from Pirate bases and the chance of spawning a Pirate base in an Unknown sector.</t>
		<t id="2021">Mercenaries</t>
		<t id="2022">Private companies not only have Traders, they also generate mercenaries over time. During their normal routine, these mercenaries will roam the galaxy, trying to be helpful where they can. Sometimes they will try to smuggle some illegal wares from a faction to another. If you happen to find one, and if you have a Police licence, they will turn Pirate and you will be able to gain a bounty by killing them. However, mercenaries can also be hired for your own benefit. If you decide to hire one, you will have to pay a regular fee and assign them one of your assets to protect or to escort. They can be dismissed at any time, but doing so below one hour is not optimal, as you need to pay a first single hiring fee that represents an hour of work.</t>
		<t id="2023">Sith Raids</t>
		<t id="2024">From time to time, Sith ships come from deep space to invade the empire that owns the most sectors in the galaxy.</t>
		<!-- Star Wars Mayhem 3 -->
		<t id="3001">Difference to Mayhem 3</t>
		<t id="3002">SWM3 is much more newcomer friendly than base Mayhem 3. Thats because nothing is really pressuring you to make progress and there is a consistent difficulty curve. The dynamic faction warfare is mostly sleeping when you start a new game. It wakes up more and more as you to establish your own player empire.\n\nBut this kind of logic also applies the other way around. Beating the base mod required days of boring preparation grind because the final OCV boss was so overpowered.\n\nThis kind of drag should be completely absent in SWM3.\nJust expanding your own empire to a certain amount of sectors triggers almost everything up to the OCV invasions. And they are unlikely to threaten the entire galaxy. With SWM3 the focus is clearly on the main factions and their wars.\nYour entire playthrough should be shorter and later more things can happen to keep it interesting.\n\nThe pacing adapts to way more different playstyles and the game doesn't demand that you make constant progress.\nEarlygame officially lasts until you claim your 4th sector. This first part of your playthrough is much less intense than it was in base Mayhem 3. If you don't know anything about Mayhem yet, take all the time you need to get familiar with the mechanics, commands and automation.\nThe gameworld remains preserved very close to its initial state. The idea behind that being that it isn't very fun if some faction completely takes over the universe before the player can even do anything about it. Like the Xenon often would in base Mayhem 3\n\nBut don't let that initial low intensity fool you! Lategame will have even bigger fleets than base Mayhem 3 and most factions will also be able to produce ships much more efficient.\n\nSo in essence you have an NPC progression which is completely linked to the player empire size. If you claim more sectors, the universe is slowly waking up and getting more active. This creates a much more consistent callenge. A slow and easy start and a more active and challenging end.\n\nIf you don't like that idea of a mostly peaceful initial empire buildup you can skip it with the new Midgame Quickstart.\n\nSWM3 removes all of the timer based difficulty scaling that base Mayhem 3 had.\nThat doesn't mean that there is no time pressure at all. Like if you go to war and an enemy Battlegroup invades you, then you obviously have limited time until they reach your sector and destroy your stations. But this kind of pressure has to be triggered by your decision. Nothing really major happens on its own even after a few days have passed.\n\nSome players might want more random war chaos right from the beginning. In this case this might not be the best mod for you.\nBut even for this crowd SWM3 holds the new Mandalorian plot. The Midgame Quickstart combined with choosing Mandalorian plot option C will create a very intense and almost completely new experience, which is heavily focussed around warfare and has much less economic grind. With that you can even control your ally's invasions to a certain degree. The risk will be much higher and the playthrough faster paced.</t>
		<t id="3003">Era System</t>
		<t id="3004">Your playthrough gets split up into 3 distinct phases. The early- mid- and lategame.\n\nThose phases change up the composition of NPC fleets. Each faction follows its own progression path which is loosely inspired by Star Wars lore.\nThere are strengths and weaknesses for all factions. More detailed info is in the Faction Dossiers.\n\nReaching a new era might unlock different ship types and other obsolete designs won't be built anymore. The factions might desire to build different fleets and also receive better or worse production modifiers.\n\nBecause the 3 phases of your playthrough are so essential, here are the two most important trigger points:\n\n- midgame starts shortly after you have conquered your 4th sector\n- lategame starts when you have terraformed 3 planets or when you own 20 sectors. Option C in the Mandalorian plot can also activate a 2 day timer to trigger the lategame.\n\n\nThere is additional difficulty upscaling in the form of Sith and Pirate strength. The two are not really dependent on this new era system, but they absolutely do get stronger just from the amount sectors you own. But overall these two hostile secondary factions are much weaker and less relevant than they were in the base mod.</t>
		<t id="3005">Hyperlanes</t>
		<t id="3006">The galaxy map marks certain sectors to contain Hyperlanes.\nWith default settings these hyperlanes only get used for an earlygame quest which unlocks the construction of jump beacons. In this quest the special sectors just represent a pool of targets where you must choose and conquer just one of them and once completed you can then ignore this sector trait.\n\n\nMayhem veterans who seek a challenge can activate a new mode which additionally restricts all your jump beacons to only work in these hyperlane sectors.\nThis is quite interesting because the galaxy suddenly gets additional landmarks which have drastic influence over your logistics, fleet movement and warfare.\nBut it generally makes your playthrough more difficult, as some areas can be very hard or even impossible to jump to. Certain other valuable hyperlane sectors might be occupied by very strong enemies. So this restricted jump beacon mode got disabled on default.\n\nBut it is recommended to try out for anyone who thinks that he has already mastered Mayhem 3!\n\nTo turn it on or off at anytime \(even during active savegames\) go to SWM3's own t-file 9973 and activate id 17.</t>
		<t id="3007">New Global Rules</t>
		<t id="3008">SWM3 sacrifices some of Mayhems typical random chaos in favor of a more stable gameworld, difficulty scaling and pacing.\nThe final part of your playthrough still has all the chaos from before, but until then there are boundaries. Especially if the player stagnates for too long and doesn't make progress with his empire building.\n\n\n- Any sort of galactic conquest from any faction \(including the player\) can only happen during the final phase of the playthrough. When the player grows he eventually triggers the final phase.\nBut if he takes too long and a major NPC faction eventually owns 40% of the entire galaxy, it cannot claim any more sectors until phase 3 gets reached by the player.\nThe Sith don't adhere to this rule and could potentially overrun the galaxy. But in reality this is extremely unlikely because they only become strong enough when the player grows larger and that also causes all other main factions to grow strong which usually already keeps the Sith in check. A few sector clusters might still get overrun by Sith though.\n\n- Major factions stop restraining themselves from claiming available neutral sectors once you own 15 sectors or more. At this point everybody will just grab the sectors he can. Growing larger than 15 sectors as the player could force you to go to war.\n\n- it is much less likely that a spawned pirate wave creates M6 instead of only fighters. This leads to greatly reduced danger during the early game and plays into the easy initial buildup. But later and in certain areas on the map the pirates can still become as problematic as before.</t>
		<t id="3009">Quality of Life</t>
		<t id="3010">- using carriers as fleet commanders works well now. The small ships which dock to them remain to be smarter fleet followers and do not become basic support ships. That means they can still be controlled with the scanning range and other fleet settings like auto-repair.\n\n- all ships have the video googles preinstalled\n\n- the repair rate of larger ships is much higher\n\n- certain actions related to the hacking system mark the affected ship names with small leading indicators \(dots\):\n. \=scanned\n\033M. \=ship is part of your botnet\n\n- maintenance factors slowly get restored in outposts which have the drydock perk.\n\n- a smaller 5km scanning range option allows you to finetune certain fleets and maximize their efficiency by staying together to the last moment and only send fighters to attack enemies which are already very close.\n\n- all ships have a preinstalled Transporter Device for easy docking, looting and for the player switching ships</t>
		<t id="3011">Recommended Settings\/Customization</t>
		<t id="3012">SWM3 comes with a preset base Mayhem 3 customization t-file in\nx3 terran conflict/addon/t/9972-L044.xml\n\nThis is a list of all SWM3 included changes:\n\n- general invasion protection threshold below which small factions get ignored and no longer invaded by others increased from 3 to 5 sectors \(certain unique exceptions to this rule\)\n\n- slower pirate respawns, delay is 50\% longer\n\n- +50\% delay between large Sith invasions which got capships\n\n- maintenance cost increases 50% slower\n\n- unlocking the final plot stage only requires to terraform 3 planets instead of 10 \(SWM3 adds an alternate trigger at 20 player owned sectors\)\n\n- no higher research costs for random ship types\n\n- disabled Mayhem's coalition system\n\n- additional waits in the capship turret script \(this doesn't hurt at all and performance is supposedly better\)\n\n- no NPC factions builds only half size squadrons when they own few sectors \(SWM3 has faction unique production discounts during different phases\)\n\n- AI ships which are waiting very long to be outfitted but can't due to a lack of resources get their weapons for free after just 1h instead of having to wait 4h\n\n\n\n\033YAll new settings added by SWM3 can be found in its own t-file in\nx3 terran conflict/addon/t/9973-L044.xml</t>
		<t id="3013">Satellite Sector Whitelist</t>
		<t id="3014">Previously the Explorer Worker ships of your satellite factories had been unable to put satellites into hostile sectors. It was also impossible to put them into sectors that you have blacklisted.\n\nBut sometimes you might just want keep your Looters or Traders away, but still want to monitor certain enemy sectors to spy on your enemies.\nThe Satellite Whitelist allows you to do exactly that. You can access it from a new button in the Satellite Monitoring screen.\nThis list puts an override on your Explorers which are now able to put and replace satellites in these sectors. Its a whitelist, so it only works for the sectors that you deliberately set up. In general you should use it sparingly, since your Explorers and satellites will get destroyed, especially if you go deep into hostile territory.\n\nBut it can still be a great way to see outside of your borders to detect incoming hostile fleets or opportunities. Depending on the sector satellites can usually survive from a few minutes up to almost forever. So don't be shy to try as knowledge about fleet movement is power! If you have a vision on an enemy which is leading a fleet formation, its ship info screen can show you to which sector the fleet is currently headed!\n\nFor your completely automated satellite spying solution simply go to your personal console and then the station settings screen for all your stations. Select your satellite factory. From there you can setup auto-assignment and auto-replacement for Explorer ships. You just need a ship template and an Outpost which should build the automatic replacements. Keeping your Explorer ship template without any lasers and using a high speed scout fighter increases the chances of survival greatly since your Explorers won't try to fight back and instead always run away when getting shot at. Any lost Explorer ships will get replaced automatically from your outpost. At this point you just need to add the sectors to the whitelist where you want to see whats going on. With such a setup there is no need to manually place satellites anymore!</t>
		<t id="3015">Combat Changes</t>
		<t id="3016">SWM3 features quite a few changes which generally improve combat and fleet AI.\n\nBut the only thing worth mentioning here is that your fleets do not attack freighters or satellites anymore. If you want to destroy these targets you now have to setup dedicated fleets to hunt them down. For this purpose there are 2 new fleet targeting priority options against Freighters and Stationary Ships. Fleets with those settings will target civilians like TS or TP and Satellites. Only once none of these civilians can be detected anymore such fleets will continue to target hostile military ships as usual.\n\nHunting freighters should work best if you split your fleets up for different purposes. Use small, very fast fighter or corvette fleets to target freighters and use a sensitive retreat threshold in order to stay away from trouble. Or have other fleets which only focus on military targets operate in the same sectors.\n\n\nRegardless of targeting priorities ships with equipped lasers will still defend themselves when actually getting shot at. Unarmed ships will always flee to a safe sation and then resume their task.</t>
	</page>

	<page id="37" title="Encyclopedia Texts" descr="0" voice="no">
		<t id="48">\033YQuirks</t>
		<t id="59">\033YSWM3 Faction Dossiers</t>
		<t id="10011">The Galactic Empire tends to have many powerful military fleets over the course of your entire playthrough. Especially their Rearguard and Border Patrol squadrons are solid, which can't be said for many other factions. This generally makes their defense very stable.\nBut their fleets are quite slow on the galactic level and they often have to deal with rebellious sectors, which are far apart and have to be reconquered. Their military campaigns often involve seemingly unstoppable invasion fleets but long travel times. They are strong, but predictable.\n\n\nIf you want to go into a permanent war with this faction before you have a strong player empire, then keeping your sectors at a great distance to theirs is probably your best and only viable survival strategy.</t>
		<t id="10012">\033G+++ consistently strong military\n\033G++ special lategame event\n\033G+ slightly larger starting territory\n\n\033R-- sectors more likely to defect\n\033R- slow fleets\n\033R- often busy hunting Rebels</t>
		<t id="10021">The New Republic suffers from low ship numbers in their squadrons due to crew shortages during the early and midgame of your playthrough. But they absolutely have the potential to grow into a real powerhouse during the lategame, where they immediately receive multiple huge buffs and instant benefits.\n\n\nThis faction is supposed to give you a lot of freedom in how you want to tackle them. They can be a very easy early target to steal a few good sectors from, or an ally for a roleplay challenge run.\nIn some rare cases they might even need your help to survive and see the lategame \(altough that should be super rare and would need to involve the Sith\)\nIn most cases they should survive. This faction is part of a big war in the lategame where many factions merge together into 2 blocks of power.\nIf you don't want this you can prevent it altogether by annihilating the New Republic during the midgame stage.</t>
		<t id="10022">\033G++++ best lategame fleets and production\n\033G++ special lategame event\n\033G+ many powerful ship designs\n\n\033R--- low ship numbers until lategame\n\033R- slightly smaller starting territory</t>
		<t id="10031">Overall the Rebel Alliance probably has the weakest, but most mobile fleets. Their hidden hyperlane network allows them to travel quickly.\n\nThe Rebels are generally always on the run, especially from Imperial Battlegroups and they usually loose in big battles.\nBut they frequently get reinforced with new sectors which defect from other factions to join their cause. This creates a very fractured and isolated faction which seems to "wander" on the galaxy map as the game goes on. They are very hard to wipe out.\n\nThis faction will start to die during the lategame, when it slowly merges with the New Republic.\n\n\nIf you plan a permanent war with the Rebel Alliance be prepared to face an enemy who is much tougher than his very few sectors might indicate. Conquering a rebel sector is no easy task due to them responding so quickly.\nAnd there is no place where your sectors will be safe from their invasions. Their fleets are not the strongest and might not threaten your existence, but they can become really annoying.\nAnd then you can also have entirely new rebel sectors suddenly popping up next to you, providing them with additional destinations to jump to.\n\nThis guerilla faction can only be defeated by wiping out every single rebel sector before the next batch wants to join them, or by reaching the lategame.</t>
		<t id="10032">\033G+++ new random sectors join frequently\n\033G++ hyperjump between all Outposts\n\033G++ efficient production \(secret donations\)\n\033G+ not invaded even if slightly larger\n\033G+ deep strikers\n\n\033R--- weak fleets, especially at gamestart\n\033R-- special lategame event\n\033R-- very small and scattered territory\n\033R- never ignored by Imperial Battlegroups</t>
		<t id="10041">The Separatist Confederacy of Independent Systems is a swarmer type faction with a heavy focus on deploying masses of cheap droid fighters. This provides the bulk of their forces with unusually high damage output, but also makes them fragile and keeps their ship production running almost constantly.\nLater they also get a lot of capships, but the swarmer focus remains throughout your playthrough.\nThe CIS doesn't have any strong or weak phases and generally just ramps its power up when the player triggers a new phase.\n\n\nSome of their offensive fleets like Task Forces can consist of fighters only, which makes them annoying enemies who are very efficient in taking out soft targets like your satellites, freighters or jump beacons.</t>
		<t id="10042">\033G+ quick station kills during invasions\n\033G+ some squadrons travel very fast\n\n\033R- frequent losses in almost all battles</t>
		<t id="10051">The Republic is the most erratic faction in the game. It starts out as an economic powerhouse with a vast starting territory, but a pacifist fleet doctrine which is loosely based on the "Rusaan Reformation" from the lore.\n\nThis weakness gets resolved during the midgame, where the Republic will perform the most intense military buildup of all factions. With huge boosts to their production efficiency and desired fleet sizes. But actually building all these new ships will take very long, leaving them vulnerable for huge territorial losses during the early- and the beginning of the midgame.\n\nThe lategame completely dooms this faction. It will become extremely inefficient and starts to slowly merge together with the Galactic Empire.\n\n\nA permanent war against the Republic can be tempting, but it is often a huge trap.\nThey start out super weak and you can literally take their sectors by force very early in the game. But the large starting territory makes it highly unlikely that you manage to completely cripple the entire faction before they can pull off their intense midgame buildup. And after this point you may get overwhelmed by a relentless wall of Venators.\nSo keep your options alive and don't declare a permanent war just yet. But attacking them is often worth it! You can win lots of good sectors this way. And their early Battlegroups are pathetic. Early on you don't need to fear their invasions!</t>
		<t id="10052">\033G+++ very large starting territory and economy\n\033G++ unique midgame boni \(Clone Wars\)\n\033G+ in earlygame not invaded even if larger\n\n\033R--- very weak starting military\n\033R-- special lategame event</t>
		<t id="10061">This part of the galaxy is plagued by hostile intruders with ships from the Old Sith Empire.\n\nHistorians have created the hypothesis that somewhere there is an automated factory, called the Starforge, which was built by the ancient Rakata. This device supposedly eats entire suns to extract their resources and then uses an unknown hyperlane phenomenon to send ships into our galaxy to haunt us.\n\nBut they seem to have limited bandwith and can only send so many ships at once. So far they weren't much of a threat.\nBut nobody could confirm this theory yet.</t>
		<t id="10062">\033G+ doesn't need resources\n\033G+ no maximum ship\/fleet limit\n\n\033R- limited waves at fixed time intervals\n\033R- only at Sith stations\n\033R- strength starts very weak\n\033R- scales with the size of the player empire</t>
		<t id="10071">This is a subbranch of the legions that the Starforge sends against our galaxy. They seem to have an independent method of transportation and can seemingly appear everywhere!</t>
		<t id="10072">\033G+ not dependent on Sith stations\n\n\033R- very long intervals between waves</t>
		<t id="10081">The criminal underworld in these parts couldn't form a very large organization yet. They have pirate bases in empty sectors and frequently start raids against the economy of all factions.</t>
		<t id="10082">\033G+ doesn't need resources\n\n\033R- no capships\n\033R- limited waves at fixed time intervals\n\033R- only at pirate stations or mandalorian outposts\n\033R- strength starts very weak\n\033R- scales with the size of the player empire</t>
		<t id="10091">unused</t>
		<t id="10092">unused</t>
		<t id="10191">When the Mandalorians got stranded here their heritage remained.\nThey are divided people and couldn't form their own faction yet.\n\nRumours have it that a terrorist organization is preparing to stage a coup, and that they are led by a new Mandalore.\n\nEventually this faction rises to power and given time, they could even threaten the galaxy. Their warlike nature demands conflict and the domination of everyone who is not respected and viewed as weak.\n\nTheir speciality are quite unpredictable attacks at sectors behind their territory border. Although their Battlegroups don't have any means of teleportation like the Rebel Alliance does and they need to take the long way.\n\n\nYou have a lot of freedom how you want to deal with this faction. When they arrive they are quite powerful and their outposts double down as alternative spawn locations for pirates. So eventually you might want to take them out. But you start out neutral and can wait for the right moment.\nThere is a special quest which allows you to form a very benefitial alliance with them.</t>
		<t id="10192">\033G+++ huge military headstart\n\033G++ very efficient midgame production\n\033G+ neutral with pirates\n\033G+ deep strikers\n\n\033R---- at war with every main faction\n\033R--- very small starting territory\n\033R-- seriously falls behind during lategame\n\033R- outposts spread pirates</t>
	</page>

</language>
